Daneen Lenora Carroll

• <u>Address</u>: 8430 Fairlight Drive, Waxhaw, NC 28173 • <u>Telephone:</u> (516) 359-0868 • <u>Email:</u> daneenlcarroll@gmail.com

<u>• LinkedInc.com:</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/daneen-l-carroll-17a7676/

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE:

Results oriented compliance, data analytics, data governance, and risk management professional with experience managing internal audits and quality assurance reviews of government, regulatory, and data management requirements. Accountable for prioritization, action planning, and risk acceptance justification through control testing, data analysis, regulatory and risk reporting across organizations and industries.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS & COMPETENCIES:

- •Compliance, Operations & Regulatory Management
- •Internal Policies & Procedures Development
- •Quality Assurance & Process Improvement
- •Risk Management & Reporting
- •Data Governance & Data Management
- Automated & Manual Control Testing
- •Control Test Scripts Development
- •Walkthrough Process Reviews
- •Data Incident Remediation
- •Business Data Domains & Data Lineage
- Data Analytics & Data Science
- Vendor Relationship Management
- Consumer Practices, Privacy & Ethics
- Complaints, Grievances & AppealsTraining & Development Facilitation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

WELLS FARGO & COMPANY

Data Analyst (Contractor)

2018 - Present

Enterprise Information Security (EIS) – Data Assessments and Controls (DAC) Team designated to monitor and perform application rationalization, report rationalization, and data controls and validations reviews of end-to-end metrics data published monthly for internal and external partners.

- Responsible for managing *EIS DAC* data controls and validations process reviews for Ten (10) EIS specific Domains with Top 84 metrics capabilities through overseeing end-to-end data governance and data integration, with a key focus on data lineage. Supporting task include:
 - Identifying metrics in scope for review prior to monthly publication to internal and external stakeholders.;
 - o Developing Key Control Review Approach Documents, data control and validation review schedules, test scripts, test scenarios & test steps;
 - o Coordinating with EIS Information Delivery Teams to ensure that calendar releases schedules and publication timelines are synced;
 - Ensuring proper validation steps and/or necessary revalidation steps are performed for metrics prior to final review phase;
 - o Confirming final reviews and approvals are secured prior to notifications and submissions final approved publish metrics;
 - Freezing and storing all published artifacts and supporting evidence in EIS DAC Team internal folders.
- Track data from the source to final destination, including assistance with data pulls, data aggregation, and automation of enterprise metric data;
- Analyze existing EIS Data Assessments and Controls to create data governance strategies, deploy recommendations and road maps;
- Manage EIS Team colleagues and business stakeholders relationships through establishing and building problem-solving partnerships to understand and define business requirements gathering, data capturing and analysis, and business rule identification.

BANK OF AMERICA CORPORATION (BAC) Quality Assurance Consultant (Contractor)

2017 - 2018

Enterprise Data Management Governance (EDMG) Quality Assurance (QA) area assigned to conduct data governance control testing for all Bank of America Corporation Front Line Units (FLU)/ Control Functions (CF) and Domains.

Performed quality assurance control testing to ensure that all FLU/CF and Domains are properly maintained, monitored, and executed data governance activities, including but no limited to: data controls, data lineage, data mapping, data movement, data quality, and tracking data defects as outlined in BAC annually approved standards. Specific QA control testing responsibilities included:

- Control testing preparation, which includes review of sampled controls, FLU/CF and Domains control testing Kick-off meetings, walkthroughs process reviews, and meeting pretesting;
- Conducting (automated and manual) control testing for FLU/CF and Domains using quality control test scripts and data frameworks
 designed to meet current bank data capture, transport, and use standards;
- Examining adherence to data quality and data movement activities, reviewing of source to target data mapping and metadata, supporting trigger, stored procedures and other relevant artifacts;
- Reviewing "Structured Query Language"(SQL) in excel and multiple databases, dashboard related performance checks, dimension analysis and reporting;
- Drafting control testing rationales explaining results of FLU/CF and Domains oversight, design effectiveness, operational effectiveness and threshold controls;
- Tracking FLU/CF and Domain data defects and remediation activities upon completing control testing;
- Performing peer reviews of team control test results, test control review by quality assurance reviewers, and final process reviews prior to submission to internal/external audit partners;
- Participating in post-control testing meetings to identify, develop and improve the quality, capability, and/or efficiency of the control testing process for the Enterprise Data Management Governance (EDMG) Quality Assurance (QA) area.

BENEFITS COORDINATION AND RECOVERY CENTER (BCRC), EmblemHealth Government Programs Quality Assurance (QA) Internal Auditor (Consultant)

2016

Medicare Secondary Payer (MSP) Contractor engaged to administer a MSP Contract for New York based health insurance carrier.

QA Internal Audit responsibilities included planning and conducting quality assurance audits on key designated work products, as well as all applicable processes and procedures for the health insurance carrier's BCRC government program division. QA Internal Audit tasks included:

- · Verifying effective resolution of quality processes and non-conformances through corrective action plan and proposed plan measures;
- Maintaining and keeping up-to-date Quality Assurance audit schedule(s) and noncompliance log(s);
- Documenting and reporting audit results to senior management and all other relevant stakeholders on process performance, activities, results, and status.

THE CITY OF NEW YORK HUMAN RESOURCES ADMINISTRATION (HRA)/ DEPARTMENT OF SOCIAL SERVICES IDNYC- Quality Assurance Coordinator (Contractor)

2015 - 2016

New York City Government Issued (Municipal) Identification Card Program – IDNYC Card Program

Ensured accuracy of information and activities of newly created mayoral program that affect diverse populations residing in New York City (NYC), which is designed to provide all NYC residents with access to a broadly accepted, official form of identification.

Responsibilities included providing ongoing quality assurance, monitoring, and testing activities for the IDNYC Card Program.

Daneen Lenora Carroll

• Address: 8430 Fairlight Drive, Waxhaw, NC 28173 • Telephone: (516) 359-0868 • Email: daneenlcarroll@gmail.com • LinkedInc.com: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daneen-l-carroll-17a7676/

Process improvement measures enhanced program execution, increased compliance standards at enrollment centers, increased rates of IDNYC card issuance, and lead to reductions in applicant card delays.

HEALTH REPUBLIC INSURANCE OF NEW JERSEY (HRINJ)

Compliance Administrator

2013 – 2015

A Health Insurance non-profit consumer operated and oriented (CO-OP) health insurance plan serving the people of New Jersey through the Federally Facilitated Marketplace (FFM).

Successfully developed and implemented a comprehensive corporate compliance and insurance compliance program for Health Republic Insurance of New Jersey (HRINJ). The program was designed to meet state & federal regulatory and legislative guidelines, support internal policies & procedures, and to help guide HRINJ leadership with complex business decisions. Compliance responsibilities included:

- Enforcing compliance & regulatory guidelines, ethics training, internal audit, privacy practice & regulatory compliance activities;
- Performing risk assessments to evaluate effectiveness of internal and external company policies & procedures and standard operating policies (SOPs), which included compliance monitoring and incident management reporting;
- Reviewing and reconciling member monthly premium payments and federal subsidy credit and/or debit payments to ensure proper end to end processing of member financial data:
- Conducting regular anti-fraud, compliance, ethics, privacy and risk training & development for staff and third-party vendors;
- Reviewing vendor manager partner data, methodologies, testing strategies, and operation practices outlined in service-level agreements (SLAs), along with business associate agreements, agent agreements, contracts, insurance policies, & company licenses.

ACORD CORPORATION 2008 - 2012

Compliance Manager

A global non-profit association working to improve data quality standards and information exchange for the insurance industry.

Primarily directed the organization's insurance forms development, forms production, and state form filing submissions process in response to state regulatory & legislative requirements and member driven data standards development requests.

- Monitored legislative & regulatory activities and participated in insurance industry & government affairs efforts in support of insurance data standards policy issues.
- Improved standardized published insurance forms in tandem with organizational development and implementation of "Extensible Markup Language" (XML) used across multiple industry "database management systems" (DBMS).
- Served as a compliance liaison between ACORD members, insurance solution providers, information systems vendors, industry & government affairs representatives and regulatory authorities.
- Regularly facilitated training and development workshops at insurance industry meetings and conferences, as well as served as a regular contributor to ACORD and insurance industry publications.

EDUCATION:

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA AT CHARLOTTE (UNCC), GRADUATE CERTIFICATE PROGRAMS AT UNCC, Charlotte, NC

Graduate Certificate in Data Science and Business Analytics (DSBA), May 2018 to Present (In progress)

Concentration: Foundational and Core Competencies In Data Science and Analytics https://catalog.uncc.edu/preview_program.php?catoid=21&poid=4586

DSBA coursework includes: DSBA 6160 - Database Systems: The modeling, programming, and implementation of database systems. Focuses on relational database systems, but may also address non-relational databases or other advanced topics. *Topics include:* (1) modeling: conceptual data modeling, ER diagram, relational data model, schema design and refinement; (2) programming: relational algebra and calculus, SQL, constraints, triggers, views; (3) implementation: data storage, indexing, query execution, query optimization, and transaction management; and (4) advanced: semi-structured data model, XML, and other emerging topics.

CITY OF NEW YORK (CUNY) - HOSTOS COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Bronx, NY

Associate in Applied Science Degree (A.A.S.):

Concentration: (Pre-Nursing Curriculum) Allied Health Sciences: Registered Nurse Program, January 2016 to December 2017

CENTRAL PIEDMONT COMMUNITY COLLEGE (CPCC), Charlotte, NC

Associate Degree in Nursing (A.D.N.):

Concentration: (Pre-Nursing Curriculum) Allied Health Sciences: Registered Nurse Program, January 2017 to May 2017

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY, ROBERT F. WAGNER GRADUATE SCHOOL OF PUBLIC SERVICE, New York, NY

Master of Public Administration: Public and Nonprofit Management and Policy (PNP)

Concentration: Comparative and International Policy Management

NORTH CAROLINA CENTRAL UNIVERSITY, Durham, NC

Bachelor of Arts: History. Concentration: African-American and Latin-American Studies Minor: English Literature

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES:

North Carolina Certified Nursing Assistant (CNA)

New York State Certified Nursing Assistant (CNA)

Clinical Internship: Sephardic Nursing and Rehabilitation Center, Brooklyn, NY

Six Sigma White Belt Certified, Aveta Business Institute

New York State Licensed Insurance Agent/Broker:

Life, Accident & Health (Life Agent/Life Broker) & Property & Casualty (Broker) (Pending reinstatement)

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

MySQL; Power BI; Tableau; JIRA; Microsoft Access; Excel; OneNote; PowerPoint; Visio; SharePoint; Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS); StateNet; Lexis/Nexis; and Westlaw